# **AKSHAY AWATE** JR. DEVOPS ENGINEER

## **Summary**

Currently working as Jr. Devops Engineer(Remote) at Unitek.ai, Ireland. 1+ years experience in software development, production infrastructure management and automation. Interested in learning new technologies and tools, contribute towards making systems more reliable and scalable, use/implement new tools to reduce toil. Availability is what takes you far in the game.

## **Employment**

Unitek.ai

Jr.Devops Engineer

Ireland (remote) July 2021 to Current

- \* Set up EKS Infrastructure with Github Actions and terraform on AWS for different environments.
- \* Wrote Github Actions pipelines for multiple environments for deploying applications on EKS clusters.
- \* Created and deployed kubernetes applications with helm using Github Actions on different environments.
- \* Worked on kube-prometheus-stack helm chart for configuring prometheus, grafana and alertmanager for different clusters.
- \* Worked on various metrics to get insights on systems and application performance including monitoring, logging, alerting using prometheus and grafana.
- \* Created multiple grafana dashboards using different datasources prometheus, cloudwatch to monitor various resources from kubernetes and AWS.
- \* Worked on multiple kubernetes objects creating deployments and mapping services with nginx on AWS Application Load Balancer.
- \* Deployed kubecost helm chart which helped to reduce kubernetes cost allocation on various resources.

Thinkingstack.ai

Banglore Sept. 2020 to Jan. 2021

Devops Intern

- \* Worked with terraform to automate the AWS EKS infrastructure.
- \* Worked on ambassador for mapping various services in kubernetes
- \* Worked on creating pods, replica sets, services, deployments, labels, health checks and ingress by writing Yaml files.
- \* Maintaining multiple kubernetes clusters involved in deploying various resources. Involved in researching and implementing POC's using OSS kubernetes tools.

CrowdANALYTIX

Banglore Mar. 2020 to Aug. 2020

UI/UX Developer

- \* Built the next version of client web application to add new user designs and features using React and various frameworks, reducing reported bug issues by over 15%.
- \* Worked on Frontend, collaborating with teammates for working up and down the software stack to tackle challenging issues of scale, reliability, security and usability for its customers.
- \* Focused on delivering user centric interfaces and scalable backend systems. Redesign and develop an existing web sites.

#### **Contact**

**■** akshayawate2012@gmail.com

## **Education**

KLS Gogte Institute of Technology, Belagavi

June 2014 to Aug. 2018

#### **Skills**

Docker Kubernetes Kafka Prometheus Grafana Terraform ELK AWS Python Go